Now called order the regular meeting for the Miami City Council.
Action item.
Proclamation declaring the city of Miami as a purple heart city.
Miss Molly.
So having just celebrated a holiday where we recognize and honor those who have
and continue to fight for the freedoms in our country.
And I got this to be an appropriate time to bring this
to the population through consideration to become a purple heart city.
A purple heart city basically honors and remembers not just those who have
left for their country but all veterans.
And those who have served in the military in any capacity.
The purple heart is the highest combat decoration that's in the military
in the city.
And it was created by General George Washington in 1722.
We were able to find that we have at least 10 known people with a purple heart.
Here in Miami, those have all the late rest of the year.
Being too representative for the purple heart city organization.
You said that a lot of times purple heart recipients don't come forward until something like this
is approved within this.
So we don't know how many people in Miami have become a purple heart city.
And what's all those who enter Miami that we have the utmost gratitude and support for all those who have served.
And so with that large population of veterans here in Miami,
you're going to have a few more minutes.
I'll make a motion.
Let's take it.
So, gold.
I've been heard.
Are you set.
I.
Hi.
Thanks Molly.
Chop.
Number three, public input and unscheduled.
Personal appearances, not.
Consent agenda.
Staff's acting.
Asking us to provide in five.
Six.
So, move.
Let's take it.
Step.
So, gold.
Davis.
I.
Number seven.
Action item.
and budget amendment 23 to 0-1 general fund using carryover funds for personnel, Jennifer.
Yeah.
So this is the other two personnel raising increases for the contract that occurred after the F5-22-23
budget was approved this now on the city side.
One of the positions of us that between MSUA and MSA.
It's just the same thing we just approved in MSUA, right?
Correct.
So, most of the time.
Most of the time.
It's correct.
Is that so?
No goal.
Number five.
Davis.
Hi.
Number eight, action item, resolution-approving community financial support
and fee waivers to K.O. car wash related to the development of 1,101 North Maine
and recommended by Mayor Parker.
So, Council, in front of you, you have a copy of the resolution, CC2022-10.
This is the counterpart resolution to the K.O. car wash resolution you approved in the
MSUA meeting and is, again, outlining the direction that we discussed and was approved
in our executive session.
Mr. Oper.
Second.
bags of chips. Yes. All were appreciated. I'm I'm exaggerating some. The
thousand hot dogs was accurate. The rest may have been maybe in the
fire department also cooked those hot dogs correctly. Yes they did. And I
want to thank the pump. Not only that, but we had a issue with water
outage. So the fire department graciously came out and helped us with some
issues with the petting zoo that needed water and a foam pit party that needed
water. So we also appreciate the fire department's willingness to help
them those. There's a community effort. I know it was hosted at the tribes
venue, but and it's in such a fantastic venue down there because it's so
wide open. I mean, you know, I've mentioned to your wife as we're watching.
It's almost like you're sitting at the front row at the movie theater right,
but it's just right there in your face. And the whole day was a lot of fun. I mean,
the turnout was amazing. Good to have asked her. It was hot. We could have been cooler,
but by the time the sun went down, you forgot about it. This fourth
July would just back, right? Sure. Well, huge, huge thank to the Peoria tribe for the
venue space was fantastic. The music entertainment that they provided, the air show, the food
trucks and all the great activities for all the kids just really make that a very special
event. And that, you know, historically was a city.
the event and now in collaboration with the Piori tribe has evolved into something completely
different and better.
Let's continue to grow and it will evolve as we go, you know, the many we can't really
call it an air show for FFA regulation purposes but it was a flyover that could potentially
turn in with enough notice, turn into an air show next year so there are some talks around
maybe expanding that, I can't confirm or deny anything at this point but we like to make
it grow to get bigger and better every year and this is my favorite holiday of the year.
I work my tail off 17 hours in the heat but I love every minute of it, it's so much fun
for me.
I thought it's better than Christmas for me, I just have a great time.
So many of the best part is all the people there enjoying themselves, having a good time, it
looks on their faces when they're, when we're giving them a free hot dog and you know, we
went by one group and, hey, you guys want some hot dogs, he's like, yeah, how much?
And I said three, he's like, oh my gosh, even better so it was great, I enjoy doing that,
I enjoy serving in that capacity and being able to provide that so.
Absolutely.
Well, I appreciate all the city folks that assisted from solid waste, parks department, the
fire department that was there in fours as well as the PD, appreciate everybody's hard work
and Molly, God love you, you did an amazing job, pull in together, everything for the booths
and the hot dogs and the chips and the water and that couldn't have gone any better and a great
job raising donations for that, which was fantastic, huge thanks to all Bart, who was such a great
partner and making sure we could do that for the community.
And we have some opportunities for improvement for next year, right?
Absolutely.
She's already been planning things for next year, she was just making a list.
Great.
That's all I had.
Thank you.
Thank you, sir.
I've got a couple of announcements.
Certainly wanted to mention Marcia Johnson's retirement this past month and wanted an amazing job.
She has done for years with our library and arts.
In her absence, Cali Cortner has been coming up through the ranks and working with Marcia for
many, many months now and it's going to be taking the reins and we're excited to welcome
her as well as the new library director.
And also, needed to announce the day and we're losing our IT director, David Ballag, is going
to be moving on to bigger and better opportunities and that'll be another big loss.
David has done an amazing job innovating here at the city and making sure that not only things
are secure but that we've got appropriate technology in place to make sure we're being productive
and able to communicate.
Medicaid and use our tools, such as Microsoft 365 and those things that make us a mobile
environment.
And so that's certainly been greatly appreciated in my short tenure that I've been here.
It was great to know that they were in great hands and had already been brought up to current
levels of technology.
With that being said, Keith Osborn is going to be stepping up into that director role.
And Keith has been working under David for some time now and has been mentored by David.
And I'm sure it will be an incredible successor to David.
And so we're excited to congratulate him in that new role.
And of course, that will leave a vacancy of his old position that he'll be looking to fill.
So that'll become...
Do my head...
Last and not least, it's hot out there.
Everybody needs to be very careful.
These heat advisories are going to be in place.
It looks like the rest of this week.
This can be extremely dangerous, as you all know, with the high temps and the high humidity.
Anybody working outside or outside for any extended period of time needs to be staying hydrated
and taking plenty of breaks.
We certainly encourage that of our city employees who are out there every day working in this
environment.
Also, of course, our electric customers need to be cognizant of these high temps and how
that relates to our electric mills.
And I know everybody fills that this time of year.
Tyler had already informed me that we had reached already hit some of our typical annual
maximums that we hit for megawatt usage for a city as a whole.
We already hit that last month in June, which is rare.
So we know that we're having already a very hot summer, and everybody's going to fill
that crunch.
And so the electric mills are no exception to that, so everybody certainly needs to keep their
blinds closed, keep the curtains closed, do everything you can to try to minimize the workload
on your AC units.
It will just kind of have to hunker down and see if we can get through this hot period.
With that, that's all I have.
Who is adjourned?
So moved?
Second.
All right.
He's dead.
Sender.
Davis.